Motivated, experienced customer focused problem solver, adept at team, people and project management. Experienced in dealing with high pressure high visibility customer facing roles. Lead two distributed teams in last company and built out teams in last three roles. Active in local Irish technology community as presenter and organiser (example).

Skills

Technical — MongoDB, Python, R and various other languages.

People — People Management, Project Management, Workshop Facilitation, Coaching and Mentoring.

Management — Business Development, Product Management, and Budgeting / Financial Reporting.

Analytics / Machine Learning — Statistics, Exploratory Data Analysis, and Machine Learning.

Design — Storyboarding, Scenario Development, Persona Generation, Task Analysis, etc.

Previous Employment

04/2017 - present Team Lead Proactive Technical Services Engineer at MongoDB Ltd.

03/2016 - 04/2017 Senior Proactive Technical Services Engineer at MongoDB Ltd.

09/2015 – 03/2016 Proactive Technical Services Engineer at MongoDB Ltd.

Focused on the development of technologies to detect customer issues and related automation tooling as well as direct customer outreach on these issues.

11/2013 – 09/2015 Technical Services Engineer at MongoDB Ltd.

Diagnostic & troubleshooting with customers as well as consultancy on architecting, developing and deploying MongoDB applications. Streamlined customer onboardings, worked with Sales on selling the value of support, and analytics for forecasting of customer demand for technical services activities.

07/2012 - 07/2013 Research Unit Manager at the Telecommunications Software & Systems Group

Formed and led a new research & engineering team in mobile services. Managed requirements, financials, staff recruitment, reporting and deliverables, in addition to software development. Developed research strategies and proposals.

05/2010 - 06/2012 Technology Transfer Activity Lead / Senior Software Developer at ICHEC

02/2010 – 05/2010 Software Developer - Technology Transfer at the Irish Center for High End Computing

Formed and led a professional services team. Initiated new client relationships, managed these relationships, captured specifications, defined and managed projects to delivery. On the technical side projects included benchmarking & capacity planning, ML models for analytics and technology evaluation.

09/2009 – 01/2010 Freelance Consultant - Web solutions development

12/2000 - 07/2009 Research Officer, various projects at the Interaction Design Centre

Technical Expertise — Examples of Work / Areas

System Engineering/Diagnostics — Troubleshooting and problem solving of large complex systems / components, architectural recommendations for data layer and benchmarking/performance guidance.

Cloud Computing — Cloud computing architectures, benchmarking for scalability / capacity planning for client's applications, co-wrote first CUDA course for Irish Supercomputer Center (ICHEC).

Analytics — Statistical analysis scripts in R, Excel, Awk and Spark.

Machine Learning algorithms for bio-medical applications (e.g. RCSI BDI CVD1).

Fraud detection prototype for subscription fraud using R, Weka and Apache (Ezetop).

Car rental analytics for up-selling identification and more robust models for demand forecasting.

Miscellaneous Applications — Various Java, Ruby and NodeJS applications for PoCs/demos.

Project Management — Examples of Work

MongoDB — Agile development managing projects within wider distributed team and organisation. **TSSG** — Agile development managing projects with US West Coast and Irish companies. A blend of single site & multiple site project teams across time zones.

ICHEC — Tailored PRINCE2 for consulting and delivered 22+ projects in 24 months to external clients. **ALL** – Mentoring, Planning, requirements specification and transformation to schedule, milestones and deliverables. Management of resources (IT & staff), progress, risks, exceptions, reporting as well as internal bidding / project selection. Design & code reviews, walkthroughs and usability evaluation.

Business Development — Examples of Work

Developed strategies targeting clients in i) Mobile Services & Telecoms, ii) Oil & Gas and iii) Finance. Planned and negotiated contracts for client accounts and managed client relationships. Managed engineering and UX teams including recruitment and annual performance reviews. Business planning, budgeting and determined client revenue targets focused at team expansion.

Courses

Project Management — Certified Prince 2 Practitioner, AMPG International.

Negotiations — Winning Negotiation Strategies, UCD Smurfit Graduate Business School.

Leadership — GRID Power to Change, GRID International.

Sales — Advanced B2B Sales Training, The ASG Group.

Lean — Lean Startup and Customer Development Workshops from ThousandSeeds.

Support — Customer Support Skills and Diagnostic Thinking, MongoDB Internal Training.

Education

Postgraduate Graduate Diploma (PGDip) in Technology Commercialisation, November 2011 National University of Ireland, Galway, Ireland — Supervisor: Prof. Conor Ryan A Generic Approach for Data Management combining Financial Modeling with Road Mapping

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Interaction Design & Computer Science, January 2010
University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland — Supervisors: Prof. Liam J. Bannon and Mikael Fernström
Investigating Methods for the Selection and Evaluation of Everyday Sounds for Use As Auditory Icons

Foundation Diploma in Training and Education, June 2009 National University of Ireland, Galway, Ireland

Master of Science (M.Sc.) by Research, Interaction Design & Computer Science, January 2003 University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland — Supervisor: Mikael Fernström Investigation of Multiple Visualisation Techniques and Dynamic Queries in conjunction with Direct Sonification to support the Browsing of Audio Resources

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Computer Systems, September 2000 University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland — First class honours

Internet / Social Presence

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/eoinbrazil
Twitter: http://twitter.com/#!/eoinbrazil

Presentations: http://www.slideshare.net/eoinbrazil/slideshows and eoinbrazil.com/presentations

Github: http://github.com/braz Website: www.eoinbrazil.com